Natasha Copeland

Creative Strategist

Professional summary

Creative Strategist with 11 years' experience developing social creative and integrated campaigns for brands in FMCG, Retail, Tech and Grocery, including Coca-Cola, Amazon Prime Video, IBM, Uniqlo, Lucozade Sport, Pukka tea, PizzaExpress, Nestlé and Rolls-Royce. Experience includes full service creative agencies, digital agencies and client-side at Coca-Cola in EMEA and APAC. Enjoy solving interesting problems. Only ever want the best work to go live. Passionate about the intersection between creativity and technology.

Contact

copeland.nm@gmail.com 07494 703448

linkedin.com/in/natashacopeland

London

Education

Awards

BA (Hons), English Literature, 1:1 University of Manchester | UK

Graphic Design | Central Saint Martins, UK

HTML, CSS, JavaScript | Code First: Girls, UK

Systems Thinking workshop | UCL, UK

UX workshop, General Assembly | Sydney

Premiere Pro, LabSpace | Sydney

Winner: Cannes Lions. Silver

Coca-Cola #colouryoursummer

Coca-Cola #colouryoursummer

Direct; Integrated Media Campaign

Coca-Cola South Pacific, company award

Outstanding Contribution to Achieving

Best use of Social & Mobile

Cannes Lions, Shortlist

Business Results

Experience

Creative Strategist | Freelance, various clients

London, UK | Apr 2019-present

- Integrated campaign planning, creative strategy, social strategy and new business pitch work.
- Client projects include Amazon Prime Video, Lucozade Ribena Suntory, Nestlé, Pukka tea, Barilla, PizzaExpress, EDF Energy, Audible, Orange (5G), Timberland and Eastpak.
- Works closely with senior creatives, delivering creative briefs and guiding creative to align with strategy and best practice, always striving for creative excellence.
- Effectively manages relationships with stakeholders.

Social Media Lead | Adcreators

Sydney, Australia | Aug 2018-Mar 2019

- Agency Lead for social, working across a portfolio of B2C brands.
- Developed strategies for platforms including Facebook, Instagram, YouTube and Weibo.
- Responsible for managing and developing a team of creative and digital specialists.

Social Media Content Producer | The Coca-Cola Company

Secondment to The Coca-Cola Company via Havas Australia Sydney, Australia | Jan 2016-May 2018

- Lead social creative for Coca-Cola, Coca-Cola No Sugar, Coca-Cola Zero, Diet Coke and Powerade for both integrated and social campaigns as part of Coca-Cola's Integrated Marketing Communications team.
- Campaigns include Coca-Cola x Kings Cross charity auction, Coca-Cola No Sugar launch, Coca-Cola Summer campaigns (2015, 2016, 2017), Rio 2016 Olympic Games (global), Coca-Cola One Brand (global) and Coca-Cola #TasteTheFeeling (global).
- Responsible for developing concepts, copy, filming, art direction and building conversational
 capital into creative.
- Managed production of video, photography, lenses and filters, live stream and music content.
- Commissioned, briefed and managed production agencies, celebrity and influencer talent.
- Produced creative guidelines.
- · Regularly presented to senior stakeholders.

Key skills & technology

Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop Facebook Ads Lightroom Google Ads Premiere Pro Google Analytics DaVinci Miro Keynote Copywriting Powerpoint AR lenses & filters Video Driving conversion Photography Brand building Live stream Influencers

Social Media & Content Manager | Ogilvy

Sydney, Australia | Sept 2014-Oct 2015

- Lead Social Media Manager for Coca-Cola working across a portfolio of brands, including Coca-Cola, Fanta, Powerade, Barista Bros and Copa Coca-Cola (global).
- Developed concepts, copy and art directed shoots and post-production.
- Other clients included IBM and KFC.
- · Regularly presented to creative directors and senior stakeholders.
- Delivered best-in-class creative. Campaign work includes award-winning Coca-Cola #colouryoursummer (Cannes Lions).

Social Media Specialist | iCrossing

Brighton, UK | Sept 2011-Sept 2013

- Launched Rolls-Royce Motor Cars brand on Facebook, Instagram, Twitter and YouTube.
- Managed Rolls-Royce social media presence live during the London 2012 Olympic Games.
- Organically grew Rolls-Royce Facebook Page to 1 million fans.
- Developed social creative and influencer campaigns for Uniqlo to engage communities and drive e-commerce sales. Developed monthly editorial calendars and attended PR events.

Volunteering

GoodGym Helping local communities and older people

Marketing Assistant | Psychology Press and Routledge (Taylor & Francis)

Brighton, UK | April 2009-Sept 2011

- Managed social media presence, focused on community engagement and driving traffic.
- Assisted Marketing Manager to devise and implement print and digital marketing activity.